<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dotnet on Coding Odyssey</title>
    <link>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/categories/dotnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dotnet on Coding Odyssey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:36:33 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.mantziaris.eu/categories/dotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NET Benchmarks</title>
      <link>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2017/07/11/net-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 07:36:33 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2017/07/11/net-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>.NET Benchmarks A lot of times i was wondering what is the best performing code. In order to determine that i had to benchmark my code, but benchmarks are hard to write. Luckily there is a open source project that does this work perfectly good and very easy.
The name of the library is BenchmarkDotNet and the documentation can be found here. The only thing you have to do is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tripping the circuit</title>
      <link>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2017/01/06/tripping-the-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 13:11:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2017/01/06/tripping-the-circuit/</guid>
      <description>Circuit breaker pattern This is probably one of the most useful &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; patterns out there and it is fairly easy to implement.
There are great articles and implementations, like Polly, already on the internet about this pattern so why another one?
 Κρείττον οψιμαθή είναι ή αμαθή.
Socrates 469-399 BC., Philosopher
Better too have learned lately than never, as he tried to explain why he learned to play guitar in his old age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To TAP or not to TAP</title>
      <link>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2016/05/25/to-tap-or-not-to-tap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 21:35:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mantziaris.eu/blog/2016/05/25/to-tap-or-not-to-tap/</guid>
      <description>TT || !TT Ramblings on Tasks, async-await and ASP.NET. The slides from the meetup do contain common issues encountered when working with TPL, async-await and ASP.NET along with some good practices. These are off course not all. Please let me know if you have any suggestions. Thanks for attenting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>